Guide to the Booker T. Washington correspondence, 1903-1916, 1933 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
- Correspondence Series, 1903-1933 and undated, (8 folders)
  - Miller to Washington, 6 February 1906, Washington, DC, 2 pages (part of page 2 missing) (Box 1)
    Published in: Harlan, Louis R., Raymond W. Smock, and Geraldine McTigue, eds., The Booker T. Washington Papers. Urbana: U of Illinois Press, 1979. Vol. 8, p. 517-518.
    Source: TLS representation Copy; BTW Papers; Tuskegee Institute, Alabama.
  - Miller to Washington, 6 October 1906, Washington, DC, 1 page (Box 1)
    Miller will prepare draft of resolutions for next meeting; reference to "Joseph" not serving their people.
  - Frissell to Miller, 25 October 1906, Hampton, Virginia, 1 page (Box 1)
    Frissell believes Miller is mistaken about a meeting in Hampton of the Committee of Twelve.
  - Browne to Washington, 26 October 1906, Cheyney, Pennsylvania, 1 page (Box 1)
    Browne comments upon scheduling of meeting between Committee of Twelve along with Northern and Southern white men.
  - Miller to Washington, 28 October 1906, Washington, DC, 1 page (left margin missing) (Box 1)
    Miller forwards Frissell's letter and suggests they accommodate Buttrick and Frissell.
  - Chestnutt to Browne, 21 November 1907, Cleveland, 2 pages (Box 1)
    Chestnutt refers to Carnegie's address and tells of his own disgust with Southern politics and their depriving the black man the right to vote.
  - Washington to Browne, 26 May 1908, Tuskegee, Alabama, 1 page (Box 1)
    Washington proposes to send Dudley Woodard to conduct study on African Americans and progress in Jackson, Mississippi.
  - Washington to Browne, 8 September 1908, Tuskegee, Alabama, 2 pages (Box 1)
    Washington disagrees with Browne and supports work in Baltimore.
  - Chestnutt to Browne, 23 October 1908, Cleveland, 1 page (Box 1)
    Chestnutt agrees with Committee in seeking Carnegie's support.
  - Fortune to Browne, 6 November 1908, New York City, 1 page (Box 1)
    Fortune does not object to findings in recent report.
  - Miller to Browne, 19 December 1908, Washington, DC, 7 pages (Box 1)
    Letter refers to "Mr. Taft's policies regarding the Negro." As there are numerous handwritten corrections, perhaps this was a copy given to Washington to edit?
  - Miller to Browne, 29 December 1908, Washington, DC, 2 pages (Box 1)
    Miller objects to Browne's tone in previous letter; otherwise, he does not object to the publication of Carnegie's address.
  - Charles W. Russell to Daniel Murray, 1 February 1909, Washington, DC, 1 page (Box 1)
    Russell reports that he has just found addressee's previous letter; comments upon convict lease system.
  - Murray to Browne, 5 February 1909, Washington, DC, 1 page (Box 1)
    Murray sends Russell's report on peonage to Browne.
  - Murphy to Washington, 8 February 1909, Baltimore, 2 pages (Box 1)
    Murphy, a printer, encourages Washington to hire African American-owned printing firms to print materials issued by the Committee of Twelve.
  - Washington to Murphy, 19 February 1909, Tuskegee, 1 pages (Box 1)
    Washington agrees with Murphy's suggestion and encourages him to correspond directly with the Committee's secretary, Browne; he adds that so far they have been unable to find an African American-owned firm capable of printing vast quantities with good quality.
  - Chestnutt to Browne, 26 February 1909, Cleveland, 1 page (Box 1)
    Chestnutt has no objection to providing Commissioner of Education with names and addresses of the members of the Committee of Twelve.
  - C.A. Coleman to Browne, 30 April 1910, Toano, Virginia, 1 page (Box 1)
    Coleman requests pamphlet Why disfranchisement is bad.
  - Marcus Garvey to Major R. Moton, 29 February 1916, Kingston, Jamaica, 8 pages (Box 1)
    (Photocopy) Garvey, a native to Jamaica, enlightens Moton on African American and native life in his home country.
  - James Weldon Johnson to Alice Marie Jones, 23 January 1933, Nashville, 1 page (Box 1)
    (Photocopy) Johnson explains origins of Lift every voice and sing.
  - Natalie Curtis to Browne, 21 May (year unknown), New York City, 2 pages (Box 1)
    Curtis requests copy of pamphlet on "Negro question."
- Printed Materials Series, 1904 and undated, (1 folder)
  Mainly contains printed material such as pamphlets and articles that deal with racial issues in the early 20th century. There are also two items specific to the Committee of Twelve.
  - Pamphlet: Why disfranchisement is bad by Archibald H. Grimke, Atlantic Monthly (original), 1904 July (Box 1)
  - Pamphlet: Why disfranchisement is bad by Archibald H. Grimke (photocopy), 1904 July (Box 1)
  - Poem: The empty sleeve, undated (Box 1)
  - Preface to Why disfranchisement is bad by Archibald H. Grimke, undated (Box 1)
  - Program from conference, New York, undated (Box 1)
  - Suggestions for Committee of Twelve, undated (Box 1)
  - The estimate of an eminent Virginian of the merit of the book 'The White Man's Burden' (original), undated (Box 1)
  - The estimate of an eminent Virginian of the merit of the book 'The White Man's Burden' (photocopy), undated (Box 1)